## Sara Alinazari

Sara.alinazari@gmail.com | 424-465-0136 | Long Beach, CA,90814

https://github.com/saraalinazari|www.linkedin.com/in/sara-alinazari|https://saraalinazari.github.io/portfolio/

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software developer with five years' experience in designing, developing, and implementing technology solutions across banking, oil, and transportation industries. Having excellent knowledge of business and processes, owing to MBA, so became a good problem solver and critical thinking. Being passionate about programming, updated programming skills, then integrate it to the ability as an analyst turned to a perfect programmer with unique qualities. Known for teamwork, striving to meet the highest standards, and for discipline and organization. Ideally suited for roles in software development, backend web developer, full stack programmer through healthcare, bio, financial, banking, and insurance industries.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Node.Js, Express, JavaScript, jQuery, React.js, React Native, GIT, Github, MongoDB, MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server, Microsoft Office, Agile Methodology, Firebase, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Media Queries, APIs, JSON, REST, AJAX, the command line, computer science fundamentals, writing tests.

#### **PROJECTS**

## North Hollywood Church https://528491.github.io/Project-1/

- Using Google and Facebook OAUTH to authenticate users.
- Using Firebase to create customized authentication.
- Executed YouTube API to show videos from channel on first page.
- Showing Facebook API to build a customized look to show their public posts on the first page.
- Get directions by applying Google Map API.

## Reijet Deal Finder https://arcane-sands-87123.herokuapp.com/

- Scoped, architected and planned site with the front end developer; An Express based web-application
- Implemented Node.js Express server using Model-View-Controller model for implementation.
- Used Sequalized to connect to MySQL as database.
- Used Passport NPM package for different authentication.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Mayc's, Newport Beach, Ca

Dec, 2017-present

Sales and Merchandising

- Provide excellent customer service to maintain current customers and increase customer satisfaction.
- Work as a team member to hit the daily sale goals. Recommend creative improvements to improve sales and service process, and shared key knowledge to train and coach team members.

#### Assurant, Santa Ana, Ca

May, 2017-Oct, 2017

Trauma Support Analyst, Single Source Processing Project

- Learned different components of the software product and their connections.
- Provided Quality Assurance analysis after each release to make sure that product follows requirements and standards.
- Understood requirements of each service and component, monitoring them to make sure they follow requirements.
- Checked different components by writing, running SQL queries in Microsoft SQL Server, using different tools to make sure that each service is working as expected.

• Liaised between business and technical teams to interpret business impacts for technical team at the same time reporting technical issues to the business side.

## California State University Long Beach

Sep, 2014-Dec, 2016

Graduate Assistant

- Used Excel Sheets for data analysis for researches and studies.
- Assisted in research, grading, and resolving problems for undergraduate students.
- Analyzed qualitative data of death because of cancer through USA in Minitab to determine the relationship between cancer and different lifestyles. Produced research study called "The Effect of Lifestyle Choices on Cancer: Which One has the Strongest Influence?"

#### Tourism Bank, Tehran, Iran

Jul, 2011-Jan, 2014

Electronic-Banking Analyst

- Researched, designed, and tested for upgrading electronic banking systems: Card Management System, Internet banking, mobile banking, SMS banking, and telephone banking.
- Designed new creative internet banking to increase the number of customers.
- Provided product support for different multiple softwares like core banking, online banking, SMS banking, telephone banking, mobile banking, and food reservation.
- Performed data analysis for preparing different reports for management.

# Negarafzar Shargh (Technology Consultant), Tehran, Iran

Sep, 2009-Aug, 2010

- Software Developer
  - Researched, designed, and implemented for a new GPS system for Iran Railway routine system (GPS) pilot project using .NET and MySQL.
  - Designed and developed an app for customers to retrieve data about different routs, railways, train schedules, and prices.

# Sazesh Rayaneh in Gas Engineering and Development Co. Project

Jul, 2007-Mar, 2008

- Software Developer
  - Supported and upgraded CMS to satisfy different needs and requirements using ASP and Microsoft SQL Server.
  - Implemented system upgrades from static webpages to dynamic website to retrieve and show data as dynamic webpages for internal or external users.
  - Managed different authentication levels to give different access for each level of users.

#### **EDUCATION**

## University of California Los Angeles, LA, CA

Feb, 2018-Aug, 2018

UCLA Boot Camp

An intensive 24-week long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications. Skills learned consisted of HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars JS, & React Js.

### California State University Long Beach, Long Beach, CA

Jan, 2014-Dec, 2016

Master of Business Administration

## Payam-e Noor University, Tehran, Iran

Feb, 2009-Feb, 2011

Master of Executive Management

### Al-Zahra University, Tehran, Iran

Sep, 2002 -Feb 2007

**Bachelor Computer Engineering**